I'm very sorry, but this is as far as I can go.
I deeply apologize to all involved.
That's all I can do.
I'm very sorry, but this is as far as I can go.
I deeply apologize to all involved.
That's all I can do.
I'm very sorry, but this is as far as I can go.
I deeply apologize to all involved.
That's all I can do.
I'm very sorry, but this is as far as I can go.
I deeply apologize to all involved.
That's all I can do.
I'm very sorry, but this is as far as I can go.
I deeply apologize to all involved.
That's all I can do.
I'm very sorry, but this is as far as I can go.
I deeply apologize to all involved.
That's all I can do.
I'm very sorry, but this is as far as I can go.
I deeply apologize to all involved.
That's all I can do.
I'm very sorry, but this is as far as I can go.
I deeply apologize to all involved.
That's all I can do.
I'm very sorry, but this is as far as I can go.
I deeply apologize to all involved.
That's all I can do.
I'm very sorry, but this is as far as I can go.
I deeply apologize to all involved.
That's all I can do.
I'm very sorry, but this is as far as I can go.
I deeply apologize to all involved.
That's all I can do.
I'm very sorry, but this is as far as I can go.
I deeply apologize to all involved.
That's all I can do.
I'm very sorry, but this is as far as I can go.
I deeply apologize to all involved.
That's all I can do.
I'm very sorry, but this is as far as I can go.
I deeply apologize to all involved.
That's all I can do.
I'm very sorry, but this is as far as I can go.
I deeply apologize to all involved.
That's all I can do.
I'm very sorry, but this is as far as I can go.
I deeply apologize to all involved.
That's all I can do.
I'm very sorry, but this is as far as I can go.
I deeply apologize to all involved.
That's all I can do.
I'm very sorry, but this is as far as I can go.
I deeply apologize to all involved.
That's all I can do.
I'm very sorry, but this is as far as I can go.
I deeply apologize to all involved.
That's all I can do.
I'm very sorry, but this is as far as I can go.
I deeply apologize to all involved.
That's all I can do.
I'm very sorry, but this is as far as I can go.
I deeply apologize to all involved.
That's all I can do.
I'm very sorry, but this is as far as I can go.
I deeply apologize to all involved.
That's all I can do.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
You don't have to apologize. It was a
lot to ask of you to begin with. Thank
you for all of your efforts up to this point.
I'll try to figure out how to go on from here.
Though even if it all goes well, it probably
won't turn out the way you'd like it.
Sending
Cancel
Sent
Please enter your name: I see.
Please enter your name: Sorry for bringing this up out of the blue.
It's Me: So at the moment, I can't help you.
It's Me: Yeah...
Please enter your name: I see.
Please enter your name: Sorry for bringing this up out of the blue.
It's Me: Yeah...
It's Me: Sorry... Time and distance are just too much of an obstacle...
That's okay. If that's the problem
then I don't blame you.
It's Me: Sorry... Time and distance are just too much of an obstacle...
Please enter your name: That's okay. If that's the problem then I don't blame you.
It's Me: So at the moment, I can't help you.
Please enter your name: I see.
It's Me: Yeah...
Please enter your name: Sorry for bringing this up out of the blue.
It's Me: Sorry... Time and distance are just too much of an obstacle...
Please enter your name: That's okay. If that's the problem then I don't blame you.
Please enter your name: I see.
It's Me: Yeah...
Please enter your name: Sorry for bringing this up out of the blue.
It's Me: Sorry... Time and distance are just too much of an obstacle...
Please enter your name: That's okay. If that's the problem then I don't blame you.
It's Me: You're my cute junior though, so I wanna help you...
Please enter your name: I see.
It's Me: Yeah...
Please enter your name: Sorry for bringing this up out of the blue.
It's Me: Sorry... Time and distance are just too much of an obstacle...
Please enter your name: That's okay. If that's the problem then I don't blame you.
It's Me: You're my cute junior though, so I wanna help you...
It's Me: Yeah...
Please enter your name: Sorry for bringing this up out of the blue.
It's Me: Sorry... Time and distance are just too much of an obstacle...
Please enter your name: That's okay. If that's the problem then I don't blame you.
It's Me: You're my cute junior though, so I wanna help you...
Please enter your name: Do you have any other ideas? Someone else who could help?
Please enter your name: Sorry for bringing this up out of the blue.
It's Me: Sorry... Time and distance are just too much of an obstacle...
Please enter your name: That's okay. If that's the problem then I don't blame you.
It's Me: You're my cute junior though, so I wanna help you...
Please enter your name: Do you have any other ideas? Someone else who could help?
It's Me: Well...
It's Me: Sorry... Time and distance are just too much of an obstacle...
Please enter your name: That's okay. If that's the problem then I don't blame you.
It's Me: You're my cute junior though, so I wanna help you...
Please enter your name: Do you have any other ideas? Someone else who could help?
It's Me: Well...
It's Me: ...
Please enter your name: Do you have any other ideas? Someone else who could help?
It's Me: Well...
It's Me: ...
Please enter your name: Please?
It's Me:
It's Me: You're my cute junior though, so I wanna help you...
Please enter your name: Do you have any other ideas? Someone else who could help?
It's Me: Well...
It's Me: ...
Please enter your name: Please?
It's me:
Please enter your name: Do you have any other ideas? Someone else who could help?
It's Me: Well...
It's Me: ...
Please enter your name: Please?
It's me:
Please enter your name: C'mon!
It's Me: Well...
It's Me: ...
Please enter your name: Please?
It's me:
Please enter your name: C'mon!
It's Me: Just kidding.
It's Me: ...
Please enter your name: Please?
It's me:
Please enter your name: C'mon!
It's Me: Just kidding.
It's Me: I know someone who may be useful,
Please enter your name: Please?
It's me:
Please enter your name: C'mon!
It's Me: Just kidding.
It's Me: I know someone who may be useful,
It's Me:if you know how to handle them, that is
Please enter your name: C'mon!
It's Me: Just kidding.
It's Me: I know someone who may be useful,
It's Me:if you know how to handle them, that is
L: I mean, I think I should be able to.
Please enter your name: Can you come that day, then?
L: I'll bee there!
L: Oh, I'm sorry. I meant "be".
Please enter your name: It'd be great if you could make it.
L: I thing I should be able to.
L:  I mean, I think I should be able to.
Please enter your name: Can you come that day, then?
L: I'll bee there!
L: Oh, I'm sorry. I meant "be".
L: I thing I should be able to.
L:  I mean, I think I should be able to.
Please enter your name: Can you come that day, then?
L: I'll bee there!
L: Oh, I'm sorry. I meant "be".
Please enter your name: We would be very happy if you could.
L:  I mean, I think I should be able to.
Please enter your name: Can you come that day, then?
L: I'll bee there!
L: Oh, I'm sorry. I meant "be".
Please enter your name: We would be very happy if you could.
Please enter your name: I'll tell you the time and place later.
Please enter your name: Can you come that day, then?
L: I'll bee there!
L: Oh, I'm sorry. I meant "be".
Please enter your name: We would be very happy if you could.
Please enter your name: I'll tell you the time and place later.
L: I'm locking forward to it.
L: I'll bee there!
L: Oh, I'm sorry. I meant "be".
Please enter your name: We would be very happy if you could.
Please enter your name: I'll tell you the time and place later.
L: I'm locking forward to it.
L: lokking
L: Oh, I'm sorry. I meant "be".
Please enter your name: We would be very happy if you could.
Please enter your name: I'll tell you the time and place later.
L: I'm locking forward to it.
L: lokking
L: looking
L: Oh, I'm sorry. I meant "be".
Please enter your name: We would be very happy if you could.
Please enter your name: I'll tell you the time and place later.
L: I'm locking forward to it.
L: lokking
L: looking
Please enter your name: We would be very happy if you could.
Please enter your name: I'll tell you the time and place later.
L: I'm locking forward to it.
L: lokking
L: looking
Please enter your name: You may know this already,
Please enter your name: I'll tell you the time and place later.
L: I'm locking forward to it.
L: lokking
L: looking
Please enter your name: You may know this already,
Please enter your name: but there's a way to avoid the auto-correct as you type.
L: I'm locking forward to it.
L: lokking
L: looking
Please enter your name: You may know this already,
Please enter your name: but there's a way to avoid the auto-correct as you type.
Please enter your name: Just press the ENTER key to send the message as-is.
L: lokking
L: looking
Please enter your name: You may know this already,
Please enter your name: but there's a way to avoid the auto-correct as you type.
Please enter your name: Just press the ENTER key to send the message as-is.
L: I sew.
L: looking
Please enter your name: You may know this already,
Please enter your name: but there's a way to avoid the auto-correct as you type.
Please enter your name: Just press the ENTER key to send the message as-is.
L: I sew.
L: I see.
Please enter your name: You may know this already,
Please enter your name: but there's a way to avoid the auto-correct as you type.
Please enter your name: Just press the ENTER key to send the message as-is.
L: I sew.
L: I see.
L: Ah, it works!
Please enter your name: but there's a way to avoid the auto-correct as you type.
Please enter your name: Just press the ENTER key to send the message as-is.
L: I sew.
L: I see.
L: Ah, it works!
Please enter your name: Anyway, thanks in advance.
Please enter your name: Just press the ENTER key to send the message as-is.
L: I sew.
L: I see.
L: Ah, it works!
Please enter your name: Anyway, thanks in advance.
Please enter your name: Oh, and while we're at it...
L: Ah, it works!
Please enter your name: Anyway, thanks in advance.
Please enter your name: Oh, and while we're at it...
Please enter your name:
L: Yes?
If you like, you could talk to your friends as well.
We only have three people so far.
If you like, you could talk to
Please enter your name:
L: Is that okay?
You're in the Classics Club, right?
We only have three people so far.
I'd be happy for you to bring along the other members too.
Bored, sitting on the windowsill,
退屈な窓辺に吹き込む風に
I frown at the wind to hide my awkwardness
顔を顰めたのは照れくさ　その裏返し
Hyouka
KamiGami
@ 湮·Molly／小然·酸菜／喵儿·小冷／时末·竭力而为
I nod uncertainly as I shape
曖昧に頷く掌の今日
the future in my hands feeling mighty
描いてる自分は少し大袈裟で
I feel that the wind is bringing change
何かが変わりそうな気がしているよ
心に呼びかける君のせいだね
I guess that's your fault for calling out to my heart
曇り空覗いた予感
The cloudy sky tells a tale of what's to come
Spread our wings with more courage than ever before
手を伸ばそう　いつよりも力強い勇気で
光も影もまだ遠くで
Light and dark are still vague in the distance
but still we want to know the reason behind kindness
それでも僕らは優しさの理由が知りたい
今は誰の名前でもない
No one so far has ever reached
輝きの彼方へ
the shining distance far beyond
全部過去になる前に見つけに行こう
Let's get there before the past takes it all
Look, he made it to the finals!
Congratulations! Made it to the finals!
Swimming club: Mizutani Shou 100m breaststroke
へえ 決勝進出だってさ
Seems so.
みたいだな
Isn't it amazing? When I see things like that,
すごいよね
去参加试映会吧！
To the Preview!
ああいうのを見ると  僕にもなにか才能がとか考えちゃうけど
it makes me wonder if I have any real talents.
But it looks like Fukube Satoshi has none in particular.
どうも福部里志には 天賦の才はなさそうだ
I'd love to believe that I'm just a late bloomer,
大器晩成に賭けたいところだけど 　望み薄だね
but I know that'd just be false hope.
データベースが何言ってんだ
Do I hear a database complaining?
そりゃ 知識に関しちゃそれなりに自負もあるけどさ
Well, I'm pretty confident about the extent of my knowledge.
But even if I maxed that out, it's not like I could become a quiz star or anything.
そんなもの極めたって クイズ王にもなれやしないんだよ
そうか
Oh?
Yeah.
そうさ 羨ましい限りだよ 全く
I'm a bit envious, to be honest.
I can think of a few things you wouldn't envy.
でも ま 羨ましいばかりでもないだろ
Like what?
例えば
Geniuses couldn't have normal lives like us even if they wanted to.
天才は俺たちみたいな普通の人生を望んでも得られないからな
普通の人生に魅力を感じるのかい 奉太郎
So you consider a normal life to be desirable?
Well, I guess I shouldn't be surprised.
奉太郎なら そうかもね
I'm not sure your life still counts as normal, though.
でも果たして奉太郎にそれがおくれるかな
どういう意味だ
What do you mean?
I know that Fukube Satoshi has no talents,
僕は福部里志に才能がないことを知ってる
でも折木奉太郎までがそうなのかは ちょっと保留したいところだよ
but I'd rather refrain from commenting on Oreki Houtarou.
俺の人生が普通じゃないってのは 人間観察がなってないな
If you don't think I live a normal life, your observation skills are still lacking.
That is to say, I'd rather not evaluate you just yet.
評価を保留したいって言ってるのさ
ところで 少し急いだほうがよくないかい
By the way, we should hurry up.
If we're late for the editors' meeting, Mayaka will give me an earful.
演習会議に遅刻したら 摩耶花がこわい
確かに
True.
まったく 夏休みだってのに
And this is supposed to be summer break, too.
遅い
You're late!
またそうやってすぐごまかす
There you go, trying to laugh your way out of it again!
How about Chitanda?
千反田は
ああ まだ来てないのよ
She isn't here yet.
心配ね
I'm a bit worried.
その差はひどいよ 摩耶花
That double standard hurts.
日頃の行いの差でしょ
You bring these expectations upon yourselves.
遅れてすみません
I'm sorry for being late!
To the preview!
試写会です
皆さん 試写会に行きましょう
Let's all go to the preview!
It's for a student movie produced by Class 2-F!
二年F組が制作した クラス展示のビデオ映画なんです
私の知人がそのクラスにいまして
One of my acquaintances from that class asked me for a critique!
感想を聞かせてほしいそうです
その相談をしてて少し遅れてしまいました
I ended up late because we had to discuss a few details.
What kind of a movie is it?
どんな映画なの
えっと ミステリー映画だそうです
A mystery, as far as I know.
面白そうだね
That sounds like fun.
Media room
ここですね
This is it.
お言葉に甘えて来ちゃいました
Thanks for the invitation! We're here!
うん よく来た
So you are.
ようこそ
Welcome,
and thank you as well for accepting my invitation.
本日は招きに応じてくれてありがとう
伊原摩耶花さん
This is Ibara Mayaka, Fukube Satoshi and Oreki Houtarou.
福部里志さん
折木奉太郎さん
私が所属している古典部の方たちです
They are the members of the Classics Club I belong to.
My pleasure.
よろしく　 私は入須冬実だ
My name is Irisu Fuyumi.
ああ やっぱり入須先輩でしたか
That's right, you're Irisu!
見たことがあると思ったんです
I knew I'd seen you before somewhere!
すまない 記憶にないんだが
I'm afraid you have me at a disadvantage.
6月末の文化祭実行委員会
At the culture fair committee meeting at the end of June,
軽音部と演劇部の争いの調停
the way you mediated the dispute between the Light Music Club and Movie Club was amazing!
あれは本当に見事でした
Satoshi, openly praising someone? Is the world ending?
里志が手放しで褒めるやつがいるとは
Sorry, I still can't place you.
やはり覚えていないな
あ そうですか
Oh.
ちーちゃんとどういう関係なの
How do you know each other?
私の家と入須さんの家でお付き合いがあって
Irisu's family and mine go quite far back,
and we've known each other since we were little.
子供の頃からお世話になっています
Must be difficult to be born into a family with history.
旧家名家もなかなか大変なんだな
Well, then.
さて これは私たちのクラスで制作した映画だ
Here's the movie that our class produced.
これを見て 是非とも率直な意見を聞かせてほしい
I'd like for you to watch it and give me your honest opinions.
I can't wait!
楽しみです
見て感想を言うだけでいいんですか
So all you want is for us to watch it and give our opinions?
それではおかしいか
Is that strange?
俺たちに不評でも撮り直しが利かないんでしょ
Even if we didn't like it, I doubt you'd shoot the whole thing again.
Do you want us to promote your film?
宣伝してくれってことですか
いいや
No.
なら見せてくれる意味がわからないんですが
Then I don't get the point of you showing it to us.
もっともな疑問だな
That's a reasonable question.
確かに ただ見てもらうだけでは意味がない
Indeed, merely watching it would be wasted effort.
でもまず見てもらったほうが効率的だと思う
However, for my purposes, this is the most efficient way.
Okay?
と
Efficient, huh?
効率的ね
このビデオ映画にはタイトルはついていない
We've yet to decide upon a name for the film,
仮称は「ミステリー」
but the working title is "Mystery".
ビデオが終わったら一つ聞かせてもらいたいことがあるからそのつもりで
I'd like to ask you a question upon its conclusion.
I won't hold you any longer. Good luck.
ではそろそろ始めよう
それでは健闘を
健闘？
Good luck?
二年F組の勇士はカンヤ祭への参加を決め
A number of volunteers from Class 2-F decided to take part in the Kan'ya fair.
They are currently on their way to the Narakubo area to gather material for their exhibition.
楢窪地区の展示取材のため 現地に向かった
We're still not there?
まだ着かないの
Yamanishi Midori
Sugimura Jirou
も もうすぐだよ あと五分もかからない
We're close. Should only be about five more minutes.
でも さっきもそのセリフ聞いたよ
That's exactly what you said last time!
Senoue Mamiko
Kounosu Yuri
It's quite tiring.
結構きついな
Katsuta Takeo
It's hot and I'm exhausted.
暑いしそれに疲れたわよ
Kaitou Takeo
It's hot for all of us!
暑いのはお前だけじゃない
さあ そろそろ行くぞ
Come on, let's go!
自主制作ならこんなもんか
Typical independent movie.
Still not there?
見えてきたよ あそこが楢窪だ
That's it! That's Narakubo.
Pretty impressive.
すごいね
なるほど ここなら取材のし甲斐がありそうだ
Yeah, we should be able to find material here.
Anyway, let's look for a place to sleep tonight.
とにかく 今夜休める場所を確保しよう
After that, we can get down to business.
取材はそれからだ
それなら あそこがいいんじゃないかな
How about over there?
行ってみよう
Let's go!
I've got a bad feeling about this.
なんだか嫌な予感がする
A mansion story!
館モノ
Mansion story?
館モノ？
It's full of dust.
埃っぽ
The roof seems steady.
どうやら屋根はしっかりしているな
It's not safe to sleep here. There's broken glass on the ground.
ここで寝るのは危ないな ガラスが散らばってる
We should find somewhere before it gets dark.
暗くなる前に 泊まれる場所を探そう
There's a floor plan here.
こっちに見取り図があるわよ
Ah, a floor plan!
お 見取り図
手分けして中を調べよう
Let's split up and check the building.
え 危なくない
Isn't that dangerous? And won't the doors be locked?
それに多分鍵がかかってるでしょ
それなら大丈夫 きっとあると思う
That won't be a problem. The keys should be here.
ええ
Is this the office?
ここは事務所か
こっちの鍵は
This key?
I think that's the master key.
それ マスターキーだと思う
なくなったら困るし 置いておいたほうがいいよ
We really don't want to lose that one, so I'd suggest leaving it there.
そっか そうだな
Yeah, you're right.
Here, take these.
ほら これ
With all these keys we should be able to check the whole building, right?
これだけあれば調べられるでしょ
じゃあ 使えそうな部屋を見て回るんだ
Let's look for a room that we can use.
うん
Okay!
普通だったらさ 全員で行動すると思わないかい
Wouldn't they normally stick together?
Your point being?
何が言いたい
Something's about to happen. Mark my words.
もうすぐ事件だ 賭けてもいいよ
俺は話しかけられたんだが
He's the one who started talking to me!
事件はこの後に起こる
And that's when it happened.
I knew it!
そうだろうとも
どうだ そっちは
Did you find anything?
鏡の破片が散らばってて 掃除しないと使えないわね
Yes, but there were some shattered mirrors that we'd have to clean up first.
I see. I found a similar room.
そうか こっちも似たようなものだ
おーい 杉村 そっちはどうだ
Hey, Sugimura! Had any luck up there?
This one's quite clean. We could use it.
割と綺麗だよ 使えるかもしれない
一旦降りるよ
I'll come back down for now.
And Kaitou?
海藤君は
まだ調べてるのか
Is he still looking around?
まあいいさ みんなで迎えに行こう
Well, let's go find him together.
控え室か
A waiting room?
He isn't here.
いないな
Huh? That's odd.
ん おかしいな
How about that?
それじゃない？
It won't open.
開かない 鍵がかかってる
It's locked.
どうしよう
What should we do?
マスターキー取ってくる
I'll go get the master key.
あ 私も
I'm coming too!
海藤
Kaitou!
ち ち 血だ
B-B-Blood!
H-Hey, is that...
ちょ ちょっと あれ
How can she take it so seriously?
よくそれだけ感情移入できるな
ちくしょう 誰が
Damn it! Who did this?
そんな
But...
終わり…　なの？
Is it... over?
まだ終わってませんよ
But the story hasn't finished yet...
映像はここまでだ
The movie is over with this question:
What question?
どういうことですか
この事件の犯人は誰だと思う？
Who do you think is the culprit?
处暑
暑将退
伏而潜处 故名也
Limit of Heat
As the Sun's strength falters,
summer's feverish heat breaks for the first time.
Hyouka
I'll explain everything in turn, but first I have another question.
順を追って説明しよう
でも　その前に一つだけ聞かせてほしい
この映像　技術的にはどう思う？
How would you rate the technical quality of this movie?
Honestly, I think it's a bit childish.
正直に言わせてもらうと　稚拙だと思います
I agree.
私もそう思う
Enthusiasm is no substitute for skill, as you can see here.
技術のないものがいくら情熱を注いでも結果は知れたもの
Is that a problem?
でも　それはそれでいいんじゃないですか
No, not really.
そう　私もそれでいいと思っている
Working for one's own satisfaction is generally acceptable.
自己満足の世界は許されていいことだと思う
出来不出来は本質的に重要とは言わない
In this case, the production quality isn't really relevant.
What then is the key flaw of this film?
なら　この企画にとって致命的な事態とは？
That it's incomplete?
完成しないことですね
そう　それでは自己満足にもならない
Exactly. Thus it is useless even for self-satisfaction.
It's shot in an unusual location,
このビデオはロケ地が特殊で夏休みの間しか撮影できないのに
so the filming needs to be completed over summer break, and that hasn't happened.
まだ完成していない
Was there a problem during filming?
撮影がうまくいかなかったんですか
Filming has been on schedule thus far,
スケジュールの消化は順調で　次の日曜の撮影で完成するはずだった
and we intended to finish at next Sunday's shooting.
Then what's the problem?
じゃあ　何の問題が？
The script.
脚本だ
The sole screenwriter for this one-hour movie was a girl called Hongou Mayu,
クラスで唯一漫画を描いたことがある本郷真由という子に
一時間の映画の脚本が託された
who was the only one in our class with experience writing manga.
そんな無茶な！
That's crazy!
She did well.
本郷はよくやってくれた
でも　彼女は今見てもらった場面まで書いたところで倒れた
But after completing the script up to the point you observed, she collapsed.
And you want us to write the rest?
まさか　続きを俺たちに？
I can't ask you that.
さすがにそんなことは頼まない
そこで　最初の質問だけど　犯人は誰だと思う？
I only have that one question for you:
Who do you think is the culprit?
Hongou wasn't able to see the script through to the ending,
本郷はこれから解決編というところで倒れた
見る者が見れば犯人を割り出すことができるはず
but it should still be possible to figure out the culprit from watching the movie.
But given that this script was written by an amateur, will there be enough clues to do that?
でも　素人が書いた脚本に　　ちゃんと手がかりがまかれているんですか
それなら大丈夫
That shouldn't be a problem.
She studied mystery quite thoroughly.
あの子はミステリーの勉強をきっちんとしていた
I believe she followed the Decalogue, the Nine Propositions, and the Twenty Rules as well.
十戒も九命題も二重則も守っていたはずよ
Moses' Decalogue?
モーゼの十戒か
No, Knox's.
いいや　ノックスの十戒だよ
The Nine Propositions and the Twenty Rules are all laws for writing mystery stories.
九命題も二十則も探偵小説におけるルールを謳った文句だよ
Yes. That means the key to solve the mystery was shown fair and square.
そう　つまりトリックを解く鍵はフェアに提示されているということ
それを踏まえたうえで　犯人は誰だと思う？
Considering that, who do you think is the culprit?
So this is why she wished us luck before.
「けんとう」ってのはこのことか
"Whodunnit" questions are beyond me. A database can't draw conclusions.
誰と言われると弱いなあ
データベースは答えを出せないんだ
Yeah, I'm really not so sure about this...
そうね　私もちょっと自信が
Though, I have a few suspicions.
怪しいと思うのはいたけど
What?
なんだよ
いや　これは奉太郎の担当じゃないかと思って
I just thought you'd be the natural choice to play the detective here.
探偵役はね
うわ　嫌そうな顔だね
Wow, I can see you're really into that idea.
I didn't watch it closely enough.
真剣に見てなかった
それなら　もう一回見せてもらいましょう
Then let's watch it again!
Give me a break!
勘弁してくれ
参考意見で構わない　気楽に言ってくれればいい
Even a few clues would be better than nothing.
Say whatever's on your mind.
Really? I think it was Yamanishi, then.
そうですか　では山西先輩だと思います
Why?
どうしてですか
She had a bad attitude.
態度が悪かったから
折木！　あんたね
Oreki! Are you even trying?
Why haven't you tried to work it out, Irisu?
入須先輩が考えればいいじゃないですか
I'm afraid mystery isn't my forte.
私はミステリーに疎くてね
Then why did you agree to make a mystery movie?
それなら　何でミステリーが題材になるのを止めなかったんですか
I wasn't part of the project when it was first conceived.
私は最初企画に参加していなかった
I took control of the situation two days ago when I arrived back from Hokkaido.
北海道から戻ってきて　事態の収拾に乗り出したのが一昨日
If I were here when they started, I'd have already nipped this in the bud.
もし私が最初から参加していたら　企画をすすめはしなかっただろう
One last question.
じゃあ　最後に
どうして俺たち古典部が選ばれたんですか
Why did you choose us, the Classics Club?
Firstly, I knew Chitanda already.
まず　千反田と面識があったこと
Secondly, I knew of the story behind Hyouka.
それから　氷菓の話を聞いたこと
You heard about that?
ご存知だったんですか
Did Mrs. Itoigawa tell her?
糸魚川先生から聞いたのか
When I took control of the situation, you were the first people I thought to ask.
事態の収拾に乗り出したとき思い出したのは君たちだ
I was hoping you might be able to play the role of the detective.
君たちなら　もしかしたら探偵役を務められるかもしれないと
I could really do without these weird expectations.
変な期待は困ります
I guess you're right.
そうだな
I must be causing undue trouble for you.
君たちには迷惑な話だったと思う　謝ろう
My apologies.
Then, let us conclude this preview.
なら　試写会はこれで終わり
Thank you.
ありがとう　ご苦労様
Goodbye.
Wait!
待ってください　それじゃあ　結末はどうなるんですか
Then how is it going to end?
I don't know.
わからない　努力はしてみるけど
I'll do what I can,
未完成に終わることも覚悟しているわ
but we may have to abandon the project before completion.
That won't do!
それじゃあ　困ります
It would be terrible if this movie wasn't completed!
このビデオは完成しないのはとても悲しいです
I don't want that!
私そんなの嫌です
I guess Irisu doesn't want that either.
嫌と言っても入須だって嫌だろう
Yeah, it'd be terrible to end it all on a sour note like that.
まあ　未鑑定のも後味が悪いよねえ
That's right... They all put so much effort into it.
そうね　せっかくみんなで作ってたのに
And why did Hongou collapse midway, putting her health and reputation at risk?
それに　それに　なぜ本郷さんが信頼と体調を損ねてまで
途中で脚本をやめなければならなかったのか
I can't stop thinking about it!
私　気になります
You should help them out, Houtarou.
手伝ってあげようよ　奉太郎
どうせ暇なんでしょ～
It's not like you have anything better to do.
Let's do this, Oreki!
折木さん　やりましょう
We'll fight to avenge Hongou!
本郷さんの弔い合戦です
本郷は死んでいない
Hongou isn't dead.
そうでした
Oh, right.
Anyway, Oreki!
とにかく　折木さん
You're eager to take up this case now, but what will you do if we can't solve it?
ここで引き受けて　犯人がわからなかったらどうするんだ？
二年Ｆ組みの先輩たちの前で土下座でもするのか
Will you get down on your knees and apologize to your seniors in Class 2-F?
I refuse to take on that responsibility.
そこまでの責任はとれない
Then how about this?
それなら　オブザーバー的な役目ならどうだろう
Why don't you act as an observer?
Observer?
オブザーバー？
You'd listen to the theories of those who would play the detective, and tell us your opinion.
私たちのクラスの探偵役志願者の話を聞いて
参考意見を言ってもらう
Okay?
どう？
I guess I can do that.
それなら　まあ
I see.
そうか　助かるよ
Thank you.
Irisu's family is quite famous.
入須先輩は有名だよ
Look, there.
ほら　あそこ
They run the general hospital in town.
彼女の家は総合病院の経営者なんだ
Oh, so she's the princess of a big hospital?
おお　大病院のご令嬢か
けど　入須先輩が有名なのはそれだけじゃないよ
She's known for more than that, though.
She has a nickname. Guess what it is!
あの人には渾名があるんだけど　なんだと思う？
さあな
Dunno.
She's the Empress!
女帝だよ
サディスティックなのか
Sadistic nature implied?
それは女王様でしょ
That would be dominatrix.
I salute you, o spirit of retorts.
その突っ込み魂に敬礼
What are you doing?
何やってんの
美貌もさることながら　人使いが荒くてうまいそうだよ
She has the looks, and she's a ruthless and smart slave driver.
Those around her end up as mere pawns in her game.
彼女の周りの人間はいつしか彼女の手駒になるってさ
Ah. That's amazing.
ほー　そいつはたいしたもんだ
But now that she's given us the chance to get on stage,
それにしてもさ
せっかく女帝がご登場あそばしたんだから
we should choose symbols of our own!
僕らもシンボルの一つくらいほしいもんだね
What symbols?
シンボル？
まず摩耶花は「正義」かな
Mayaka would be Justice,
though I considered Judgment as well.
「審判」と迷ったんだけどね
What are you talking about?
なんだ　それ
タロットのことだよ
Tarot, of course.
What would you be, then?
じゃあ　福ちゃんはなんなのよ
Let's see... The Fool? Actually, more like the Magician.
そうだね　「愚者」　いや　「魔術師」かな
I'll leave the Fool for Chitanda.
「愚者」は千反田さんに譲るよ
That's right...
そうですね　言われてみれば　「愚者」かなと思います
Now that you mention it, I guess I could be the Fool.
I guess that's my downside?
そこが私の良くないところかもしれませんけど
I don't get it.
わかんない
Me neither.
俺もだ
折木さんは
And Oreki?
そりゃ決まってるよ　「力」さ
That's obvious. He's Strength.
え　そうですか　私は「星」がいいと思うんですが
Really? I'd say he's more like the Star.
No, it must be Strength. It fits him perfectly.
いや　絶対「力」だね　ばっちりだよ
It doesn't sound like you're praising me.
褒めているわけじゃなさそうだな
That's not true either.
そうでもないさ
He's such a pain.
忌々しい奴だ
Not happening.
無理だ
Yes?
はい
Good morning!
おはようございます　迎えに来ちゃいました
I've come for you!
What a princess.
なんてお嬢様だ
Good morning!
おはようございます
Morning!
おはよう
今日は使いの方に案内してもらって
Today we'll meet up with a guide who'll take us to these would-be detectives.
探偵役の方に話を伺いましょう
いつの間に打ち合わせしたの？
How did you set that up?
チャットです
On the net.
There's a students-only chat room on the school's homepage.
神山高校のホームページに　生徒だけ入れるチャットルームがあるんです
へえ　そんなのがあるの　今度教えて
Really? I had no idea.
Show me next time!
Sure.
いいですよ
はい　どうぞ
Come in!
Is this the Classics Club's room?
古典部の部室はここですか
はい　あなたは二年Ｆ組の方ですか
Yes. Are you from Class 2-F?
My name is Eba Kurako.
江波倉子と言います
Nice to meet you.
よろしくお願いします
I think Irisu mentioned this to you already,
入須から話があったと思いますが
but today I'll be introducing you to the people who would play the detective.
今日はこれからみなさんを探偵役に引き合わせます
Let's get going.
では　行きましょう
Chi, is that a box of sweets?
ちいちゃん　それお菓子？
Yes, they're some chocolates we were given.
はい　今日はいただきもののチョコレートです
I thought it might be nice to pass them around while we talk.
みなさんで食べながらお話しようと思いまして
Good idea!
いいね
You can't think on an empty stomach, after all.
お腹が空いては頭が働かなくなってしまいますし
I'm looking forward to hearing what theory you'll come up with this time, Houtarou.
どんな推理を聞かせてもらえるのかな　楽しみだね　奉太郎
Oh, I bet you're all having a great time.
お前らみんな楽しそうだな
先輩　質問していいですか
Eba, could I ask you a question?
Go on.
どうぞ
誰の話を聞くんですか
Who are we going to meet?
The assistant director, the prop master and the marketing manager.
助監督と小道具　広報の三人です
ええ　ちなみに江波先輩は何を担当していたんですか
And what was your job?
I stayed out of this whole affair.
私は企画に参加していません　興味がなかったので
It didn't interest me.
An excellent answer that I approve of.
実に俺好みのいい回答だ
江波さんは本郷と親しかったんですか
Were you close to Hongou?
Why do you ask?
どうしてですか
I was just interested as to what kind of person wrote the script.
いいえ　ただあの脚本を書かれた方がどのような方だったのか
気になるだけです
She's...
本郷は生真面目で注意深く
earnest and careful,
has a strong sense of duty, and she's so kind it's almost foolish.
責任感が強くて馬鹿みたいにやさしく　脆い
She's fragile.
She's my best friend.
私の親友です
I see.
そうですか
We're here.
ここです　現在映画の製作は中断していますので
Right now the production of the movie is on hold,
おそらく誰も来ないでしょう
so I doubt anyone else will stop by.
Here are our would-be detectives.
この三人が探偵役志願者です
今夜恋に変わる　幸せな夢で会おう
Let us meet in a blissful dream tonight, let it be our love
きっと　ねぇ見つけてね
Find me, I beg you
まどろみの約束
We promised to meet, drifting in and out of sleep
芽生えてた温もり　暖かくて戸惑う
This sprouting warmth confuses us
こんな気持ちをまだ　あなたは分からないよ
Don't you understand this feeling yet?
そんな視線には意味なんて　別にないはず
Normally such random glances hold no meaning
だって友達にしてるのと同じ
Isn't it the same when making friends?
明け方に消えてく　小さな願星
The little shooting stars we wish upon, vanishing into the dawn
夜の間だけの魔法を…
are a magic that only unfolds in the night
今夜恋に変わる　幸せな夢で会おう
Let us meet in a blissful dream tonight, let it be our love
きっと　ねぇ見つけてね
Find me, I beg you
まどろみの約束
We promised to meet, drifting in and out of sleep
次回　古丘廃村殺人事件
Next time: Murder in the Ghost Town of Furuoka.
Murder in the Ghost Town of Furuoka